Boladji **Vinny** ADJIBI

Atlanta, GA, USA **(**404) 319-9952

✓ vinny.adjibi@gatech.edu

Self-motivated researcher with more than a year experience, I am interested in the possible uses of machine learning for cybersecurity problems. Over a period of two semesters, I was able to conduct a thorough analysis of online learning algorithms for botnet detection, which resulted in promising results. Driven by the need to contribute to the security challenges in Africa, I currently, conduct research that leverages machine learning to significantly reduce the cost of cybersecurity solutions.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosophy in Electrical and Computer Engineering 2019 - 2021

Research Area: Security solutions for SMEs Georgia Institute of Technology, GA, United States of America.

Master of Science in Information Technology 2019 - 2021

Specializations: Cybersecurity, Applied Machine Learning Carnegie Mellon University, PA, United States of America.

2015 - 2018 **Bachelors Degree in Computer Science**

Specializations: Information Technology Security.

Institut de Formation et de Recherche en Informatique, University of Abomey-Calavi, Benin.

PAPERS

1. **Boladji Vinny Adjibi**, Fatou Ndiaye Mbodji, Tegawendé F. Bissyandé, Kevin Allix, Jacques Klein, "The Devil is in the Details: Unwrapping the Cryptojacking Malware Ecosystem on Android", 2022 IEEE International Workshop on Source Code Analysis and Manipulation (SCAM) 2024

AWARDS

Distinguished Artifact Reviewer Award

Annual Computer Security Applications Conference (ACSAC) 2023

Lakshmi Subramanian CMU-Africa Student Excellence Award

Awarded for having best inspired fellow students to a love of learning through a combination of intellect, high scholarly achievement, engagement with the CMU-Africa community, and character.

Best Student Award 2017

Being awarded the prize for having the best results in my university for the academic year 2016-2017.

National Mathematics and Physics Contest, Benin

Ranked 8th in the national contest (2010) organized by the Abdus Salam Institute and the Institute of Mathematics and Physics Science.

WORK EXPERIENCE

August 2022 - Present

Graduate Research Assistant

Astrolavos Lab, Georgia Institute of Technology, USA

January 2022 - August 2022 Research & Development Specialist

TRuX, University of Luxembourg, Luxembourg

- Researched crypto mining applications in the Android ecosystem.
- Developed a new methodology to identify smart contracts hierarchy with a 100% confidence degree, outperforming existing techniques.

June 2021 - December 2021 Research Assistant

Carnegie Mellon University Africa, Kigali, Rwanda

- Designed and implemented an SDN controller that detect changes in an online fashion for automatic fault recovery.
- · Designed an application that allows for mass handwritten words data collection despite the COVID-19 pandemic.
- Created two hacking challenges to be used in a new Capture The Flag competition.

November 2020 – April 2021 Cloud Engineer

Oltranz Ltd, Kigali, Rwanda

- Centralized the process to deploy application to the cluster by customizing and extending the Gitlab CI/CD pipeline.
- Removed errors in deployment by creating a custom Helm chart repository that dictates the components for every deployment.
- Reduced time to deploy to Jenkins by 30% by updating a script that creates the deployment file based on a simple configuration file.

February 2021 - May 2021

Graduate Teaching Assistant - Cognitive Robotics

Carnegie Mellon University Africa, Kigali, Rwanda

- Developed example applications in ROSLISP and C++ to support the learning experience for the students.
- · Provided support and helped students work through their assignments through regular office hours.

August 2020 - October 2020

Graduate Teaching Assistant - Mathematical Foundations of Machine Learning

Carnegie Mellon University Africa, Kigali, Rwanda

- Created 5 programming assignments ranging from simple matrix computation to implementing some machine learning algorithms such as Ridge Regression, PCA, and SVD reduction.
- Supported student's performance in programming tasks by setting up auto graders with Python.

May 2020 - August 2020

Research Assistant

Carnegie Mellon University Africa, Kigali, Rwanda

- Improved the accuracy of tasks executed by the robot model to 90% by tuning PID values and setting appropriate dynamics variables.
- Created a ROS package to control the robot model and environment using LISP and C++.

September 2018 – June 2019

Fullstack Web & Mobile Developer

JMA Plus, Cotonou, Benin

- Increased customer satisfaction by modifying Joomla and WordPress extensions to fit their needs.
- Improved application performance by 10% using efficient queries leveraging the Laravel database API.

March 2018 - September 2018

Junior Web & Mobile Developer

Emmac Corporation, Cotonou, Benin

- Improved a Java-based recruitment application performance by 15% by refactoring the code.
- Delivered mobile applications 50% faster than previously by using a Scrum methodology.

July 2016 - September 2017

Front Office Engineer

Huawei Technologies Benin, Cotonou, Benin

- Reduced the incident reporting speed to less than 5 mn by developing a JavaScript application that parses sites that are down from nodes' query output.
- Improved the time to generate a weekly report by creating a Python script that parses and analyzes the data automatically with minor modifications on hand later.

RELEVANT PROJECTS

August 2020 - May 2021

Masters' Thesis: Improving botnet activity detection using online learning

Masters' student.

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1e4nrw10LFjIsNXmt16kZqqZuAdP3Rgf_/view?usp=sharing

Tools and languages used: Slurm, Bash, Python, LATEX.

Abstract: Over a period spanning two semesters, various online learning algorithms have been trained and compared to existing techniques in a bid to find resilient detection techniques. At the end of the project, the detection model outperformed the existing techniques.

March 2020-March 2020

Penetration testing for the Rwanda Information Security Agency

Red teamer.

Tools and languages used: Metasploit, Burp Suite, Open VAS, nmap, Python. **Abstract:** This project consisted in performing a penetration testing of the websites developed by the Rwanda Information Security Agency (RISA).

SKILLS

Cyber Security

(advanced) Kali Linux, Open Source Intelligence, (intermediate) Logs analysis, Cloud security, (beginner) Dynamic and Static Malware analysis.

Programming Languages

(advanced) Python, Java, Java Android, (intermediate) C++, Javascript, PHP, Bash, Lisp (low) Ruby, C.